Guide to the Durham Bicentennial Commission Records, 1974-1977
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Bicentennial Commission records 1974-1977
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham (N.C.) Bicentennial Commission
3.5 linear feet Extent: 504 Items
The Durham Bicentennial Commission, officially registered as the Durham-County American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, was a Durham County, N.C. organization responsible for coordinating and planning events to celebrate the American Bicentennial in 1976. Collection contains materials relating to the various activities sponsored by the Commission, the members of the various committees, financial records in the collection and the participants in the Folklife and Summer Arts festivals held in 1976. The lists of potential participants and actual participants name numerous artists, craftpersons, and musicians. Included also are three oversize maps of the NC Bicentennial Folklife Festival grounds. The official name of the Commission as registered with the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration was The Durham-County American Revolution Bicentennial Commission.
RL.00342
Language: Material inEnglish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Bicentennial Commission Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1983.
Historical Note
The Durham Bicentennial Commission, officially registered as the Durham-County American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, was a Durham County, N.C. organization responsible for coordinating and planning events to celebrate the American Bicentennial in 1976.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials relating to the various activities sponsored by the Commission, the members of the various committees, financial records in the collection and the participants in the Folklife and Summer Arts festivals held in 1976. The lists of potential participants and actual participants name numerous artists, craftpersons, and musicians. Included also are three oversize maps of the NC Bicentennial Folklife Festival grounds. The official name of the Commission as registered with the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration was the Durham-County American Revolution Bicentennial Commission.
Subject Headings
Durham Bicentennial Commission; American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976; Celebrations -- Durham (N.C.); Durham (N.C.) -- History; Durham County (N.C.) -- History; Folk festivals -- North Carolina; North Carolina Bicentennial Committee
Contents of Collection
- Durham Bicentennial Commission Records, 1974-1977, (7 boxes)
  - American Revolution Bicentennial Administration (Box 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation (Box 1)
  - Bicycle Routes (Box 1)
  - "The Black Man in Art," Durham Chautauqua, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Blacks's History (Box 1)
  - Budget and Financial Reports, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Bull City Blues (Box 1)
  - Bull Durham and Beyond (Box 1)
  - Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Calvert Method School (Box 1)
  - Carr, Julian Shakespeare. Home (Box 1)
  - Chapman, Robert L. (Box 1)
  - Contracts (Box 1)
  - Correspondence. (General) (Box 1)
  - Crafts (Box 1)
  - Dance and Music and Drama (Box 1)
  - Diorama of Durham's History (Box 1)
  - Downtown Revitalization Committee (Durham): Downtown Update (Box 1)
  - Duke Homestead (Box 1)
  - "The Dukes" by Buck Roberts (Box 1)
  - Durham Bicentennial (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial. Miscellany (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Commission. Accounts (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Commission. General Journal (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Commission. Minutes (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Festival. Field Workers (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial News: Now and Then (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial News: Now and Then. Mailings Labels (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Plan, 1975, June 18 (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Steering Committee. Budgets and Financial Reports (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Steering Committee. Correspondence; Membership Lists (Box 2)
  - Durham Bicentennial Steering Committee. Minutes (Box 2)
  - Durham Centennial, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Durham Churches. List (Box 2)
  - Durham City and County Schools (Box 2)
  - Durham Civic Choral Society (Box 2)
  - Durham County Historic Sites (Box 2)
  - Durham Hotel (Box 2)
  - Durham Station Happening (Box 2)
  - Exhibition in Black Cultural Experiences (Box 2)
  - Fairntosh (Box 3)
  - Festival Committee Members; Correspondence, etc. (Box 3)
  - Festival of the Fourth. 1976, July (Box 3)
  - Festival Projects (Box 3)
  - Festival USA (Box 3)
  - Film of the History of Durham (Box 3)
  - Forum Committee (Box 3)
  - Gardening. Community Garden Proposal (Box 3)
  - Gardening. Community Gardening Project (Box 3)
  - Gardening. Durham County Gardening Association (Box 3)
  - Gardening. Flower Garden Contest (Box 3)
  - Gifts (Box 3)
  - Girlfriends, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Grant Applications (Box 3)
  - Green Survival '76 (Box 3)
  - Heritage. Committee Members and Minutes of Meetings, etc. (Box 3)
  - Heritage. Grants Committee (Box 3)
  - Heritage. Projects (Box 3)
  - Hill, George Watts (Box 3)
  - Hill, John Sprunt (Box 3)
  - Hillside High School. History (Box 3)
  - Historic Places in Durham and Durham County (Box 3)
  - Historic Preservation Society of Durham (Box 3)
  - Historic Preservation Society of N.C. (Box 3)
  - History of Austin-Heaton Company (Box 3)
  - Horizons Committee (Box 3)
  - Information and Referral Service of Durham County (Box 4)
  - Internal Revenue Service Extension Applications (Box 4)
  - James O'Kelly - Southern Champion of Christian Liberty (Box 4)
  - Kiwanis Club of Durham, Inc. (Box 4)
  - Learning Institute of North Carolina (Box 4)
  - Lenox Baker Cerebral Palsy and Crippled Children's Hospital of North Carolina (Box 4)
  - McDaniel, George. Project: "Fish Dam and Slave Quarters: The Tri-Racial Cultures of the Cameron Plantation." (Box 4)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 4)
  - Maps (Box 4)
  - Mini Museum of Durham History (Box 4)
  - Mount Bethel united Methodist Church. History (Box 4)
  - Municipal Grant Application (Box 4)
  - National Register of Historic Sites (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. County Organizations (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Cash Workpapers, 1976; Accounting System (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Check folder No. 1 (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Check folder No. 2 (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Expenditure Requisitions (Box 5)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Financial Records (Box 5)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. General Journal (Box 5)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Ledger (Box 5)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Media (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Overview (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Program (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Taxes (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Folklife Festival. Track Plan (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Parade, 1976, July 3; Festival for the Fourth, 1976, July 4 (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Bicentennial. Planning Guide (Box 6)
  - Oral History. Interview of Irving Allen (Box 6)
  - "An Oral History of West Durham: A Report Submitted to the Durham Bicentennial" (Box 6)
  - Pictures. Washington Duke (former) Hotel (Box 6)
  - "The Pioneers of Durham" by Buck Roberts (Box 6)
  - Press Releases (Box 6)
  - Publicity Committee (Box 6)
  - Rose of Sharon Baptist Church. History (Box 6)
  - "Snow Hill and the Transylvania Company" (Box 6)
  - Southern Conservatory of Music (Box 6)
  - Southern Railroad (Box 6)
  - Southern Railway Exhibit Car (Box 6)
  - Stagville (Box 6)
  - "Staggville--1799" by Buck Roberts (Box 6)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Crafts (Box 6)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Duke University (Box 7)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Pan Africa - USA Track Meet, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Planning Guide (Box 7)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Rejected File (Box 7)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Visual Artists (Box 7)
  - Summer Arts Festival. Visual Arts (Box 7)
  - "The Sword of Peace," Snow Camp, N.C. (Box 7)
  - Trinity Park Association (Box 7)
  - Walking Tour Guide. Raleigh, N.C. (Box 7)
  - Watts Hospital (Box 7)
  - White Rock Baptist Church. History (Box 7)
  - Yates Baptist Church. History (Box 7)
  - Maps of the N.C. Bicentennial Folklife Festival grounds (Opaperfolder OC:I:4)